Inventory of the Edward J. Rozek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- First Polish Armoured Division Materials, 1979-2001 (Boxes 93-95)
  - Pancerniak Newsletter, no. 14-54, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 94: 1-8)
    Newsletter of the First Polish Armoured Division Veterans Association
  - Pancerniak Newsletter, no. 55-70, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 95: 1-6)
    Newsletter of the First Polish Armoured Division Veterans Association.
- Notecards, 1961 (Box 95)
  Index and notecards with miscellaneous sayings and idioms.
  - Sayings and notes on index cards, 1961 (Box-folder 95: 7-9)
- Oversized Materials, 1960-1981 (Box 96)
  - Lithograph print of Warsaw, undated
  - Solidarity Polish Trade Union poster, 1981
  - Various newspaper reprints of ads and articles authored by Edward Rozek, undated
  - Advertisements for W.F. Dyde Student Forum speakers, 1960s
- Sound Recordings, 1972-1998, 2003 (Boxes 97-130, 149-151)
  - 7" reels (Boxes 97-98, 100-104)
  - 5" reels (Boxes 99, 103-106)
  - 3" reels (Boxes 105-106)
  - 8-Track (Box 130)
  - Sound cassettes, 1972-1998, 2003; 1022 sound cassettes (Boxes 107-129, 149-151)
    - 1972 Institute tapes, 1972 June 19 - September 22
      - Wolfe, Teller, Hook, and Erickson lectures, 1972 June 19 (Box 107)
        Access
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011827
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Edward Teller; Part 3: Sidney Hook; Part 4: John Erickson
      - Hewes, Hook, Erickson, and Wolfe lectures, 1972 June 20 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011838
        Part 1: Hewes; Part 2: Hook; Part 3: Erickson; Part 4: Wolfe
      - Erickson and Wolfe lectures, 1972 June 21 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011844
        Part 1: Erickson; Part 2: Wolfe
      - Erickson lecture, 1972 June 22 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011845
      - Erickson lectures, 1972 June 23 and 26 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011859
        Part 1: 23 June 1972; Part 2: 26 June 1972
      - Wolfe and Judd lectures, 1972 June 26 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011860
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Walter Judd
      - Byne, Wolfe, St. John-Stevas, and Erickson lecture, 1972 June 27-28 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011865
        Part 1: Byrne, 27 June 1972; Part 2: Wolfe, 27 June 1972; Part 3: St. John-Stevas, 27 June 1972; Part 4: Erickson, 28 June 1972
      - Judd and Wolfe lectures, 1972 June 28 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011866
        Part 1: Walter Judd; Part 2: Bertram Wolfe
      - Judd and St. John-Stevas lectures, 1972 June 29 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011867
        Part 1: Judd; Part 2: St. John-Stevas
      - Wolfe, Judd, and St. John-Stevas lectures, 1972 June 30 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011873
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Walter Judd; Part 3: Walter Judd; Part 4: Norman St. John-Stevas
      - St. John-Stevas and Erickson lecture, 1972 July 3-4 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011879
        Part 1: St. John-Stevas, 3 July 1972; Part 2: Erickson, 4 July 1972
      - Judd and Wolfe lectures, 1972 July 3 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011883
        Part 1: Judd; Part 2: Wolfe
      - Erickson and Hook lectures, 1972 July 3 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011884
        Part 1: Erickson; Part 2: Hook
      - Wolf and St. John-Stevas lectures, 1972 July 4 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011885
        Part 1: Wolfe; Part 2: St. John-Stevas
      - Hook and Judd lectures, 1972 July 5 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011889
        Part 1: Hook; Part 2: Judd
      - Wolfe and Elliot lectures, 1972 July 5 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011890
        Part 1: Wolfe; Part 2: Elliot
      - Erickson lectures, 1972 July 5-6 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011894
        Part 1: 5 July 1972; Part 2: 6 July 1972
      - Papp and Mott, 1972 July 5 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011893
        Part 1: Papp; Part 2: Mott
      - Wolfe and St. John-Stevas lectures, 1972 July 6 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011901
      - Walt and Judd lectures, 1972 July 6 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011902
        Part 1: Lewis Walt speaks on the illegal drug trade.; Part 2: Walter Judd
      - Judd and Wolfe lectures, 1972 July 7 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011903
      - Rozek and Hook lectures, 1972 July 7 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011904
        Part 1: Rozek; Part 2: Hook
      - Edward Teller lecture, 1972 September 15 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011905
      - Edward Teller lecture (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011906
        Teller examines the war between Japan and the United States during World War II, especially in regards to the atomic bomb. He argues the United States should not have used the bomb, that it should have simply demonstrated it without human casualties.
        Following, he examines foreign influences in Southeast Asia, focusing on French, Japanese, and American involvement in the area. During this segment, he mentions what might happen under McGovern should he win the election, indicating the talk is from sometime in 1972.
      - Edward Teller lecture, "Three Hundred Million,", 1972 September 22 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011907
    - 1973 Institute tapes, 1973 June 5 - July 3
      - Judd and Teller lectures, 1973 June 5 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011914
        Part 1: Walter Judd; Part 2: Edward Teller
        Squeaking throughout the recordings is present in the audio on the accessioned cassette.
      - Teller and Malik lectures, 1973 June 18 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011915
        Part 1: Edward Teller; Part 2: Charles Malik
      - Wolfe and Judd lecture, 1973 June 18-19 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011923
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe, 18 June 1973; Part 2: Walter Judd, 19 June 1973
      - Teller and Malik lectures, 1973 June 19 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011925
      - Nichols and Judd lecture, 1973 June 19-20 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011931
        Part 1: Nichols; Part 2: Judd
      - McKean guest lecture and Teller lecture, 1973 June 20-21 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011932
        Part 1: Dayton McKean guest lecture, 20 June 1973; Part 2: Edward Teller, 21 June 1973
      - Teller and Malik lectures, 1973 June 20 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011935
      - Stewart lecture, 1973 June 20 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011949
      - Judd and Teller lectures, 1973 June 21 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011936
        Part 1: Walter Judd lecture on Chinese culture.; Part 2: Edward Teller
      - Malik and Teller lecture, 1973 June 21-22 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011943
        Part 1: Charles Malik; Part 2: Edward Teller
        There is a dropout in part 1 at 10:44. This is due to a problematic section of tape that could only be solved by a careful splice of the tape during transfer. A corresponding dropout is audible on part 2, likely around the 50 min mark.
      - Hughes and Judd lecture, 1973 June 21-22 (Box 107)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011944
        Part 1: Albert Hughes; Part 2: Walter Judd
      - Wolfe and Belmont lectures, 1973 June 25 (Box 107)
        Unfortunately, the accessioned tape is blank. Lectures are unavailable.
      - Judd and Teller lectures (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011981
      - Malik and Wolfe lectures (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011982
        Part 1: Charles Malik; Part 2: Bertram Wolfe
      - Malik and unidentified lectures, 1973 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011987
        Part 1: Charles Malik; Part 2: unidentified
      - Walt and Russell lectures, 1973 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011988
        Part 1: Lewis Walt; Part 2: J. Russell
      - Charles Malik and Bertram Wolfe lectures, 1973 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011993
        Part 1: Charles Malik
      - Unidentified conversation (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011994
        This recording is a conversation among various people. The only speaker that seems to be "on mic" is Edward Teller.
      - Belmont and Wolfe lectures, 1973 June 25 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011955
        Part 1: Belmont; Part 2: Wolfe
      - Wolfe and Mephis lectures, 1973 June 26 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011956
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Mephis
      - Wolfe and Malik lectures from, 1973 June 27 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011967
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Charles Malik
      - Teller and Sears lectures, 1973 June 27 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011968
        Part 1: Edward Teller; Part 2: Richard Sears
      - Paget lecture, 1973 June 27 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011969
      - Malik and Wolfe lectures, 1973 June 28 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011970
        Part 1: Malik; Part 2: Bertram Wolfe
      - Harris and Teller lectures, 1973 June 28 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011971
        Part 1: Frank E. Harris; Part 2: Edward Teller
      - Ward Elliott lecture (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011972
      - Teller and Malik lectures, 1973 June 29 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011974
      - Judd and Teller lectures, 1973 July 2 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011976
      - Judd and Teller lectures, 1973 July 2-3 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011977
        Part 1: Walter Judd, p.m., 2 July 1973; Part 2: Edward Teller, 3 July 1973
      - Judd and Wolfe lectures, 1973 July 3 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011975
      - Sawyer and Teller lectures, 1973 June 26 (Box 108)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011959
        Part 1: "Tom" Sawyer; Part 2: Edward Teller
    - Conference on Advanced Energy Systems, 1974 June 20-21 (Box 108-109)
      Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0011999
      A conference on physics and energy systems with several speakers.
      Please note that each cassette exists in the Archives in triplicate. All three copies have similar sound quality, which, unfortunately, is poor due to distortion.
    - Land Use Conference, 1975 May 19-20 (Box 109)
      Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012013
      Part 01: May 19. Conference introduction: Brett, morning speeches: Lamm, Harrigan, Herst (part 1)
      Part 02: May 19. Herst (cont'd); Draine; panel: Crowley, Drachman, Rockwell, Shepard (part 1)
      Part 03: May 19. Morning Panelist Statement: Shepherd(part 2)
      Part 04: May 19. Morning Panelist Statement: Daggett, panel discussion, Q&A, Luncheon (part 1)
      Part 05: May 19. Luncheon (part 2), afternoon speeches: Moses (part 1)
      Part 06: May 19. Afternoon speeches: Moses (part 2), Berg (part 1)
      Part 07: May 19. Afternoon speeches: Berg (part 2), McClaughry, panelists: Bermingham, Draine (part 1)
      Part 08: May 19. Afternoon panelist statement: Draine (part 2), panel discussion
      Part 09: May 19. Afternoon panel discussion (part 2), Q&A
      Part 10: May 19. Entire evening session.
      Part 11: May 20. Morning speeches: Hoegh, Thomas, McCloskey (part 1)
      Part 12: May 20. Morning session. McCloskey (part 2), Bannister
      Part 13: May 20. Morning panelist statements, panel discussion Q&A (part 1)
      Part 14: May 20. 10:15, Q&A
      Part 15: May 20. Morning: Q&A (last part), afternoon speeches: Roth, McCredie, Orell (part 1)
      Part 16: May 20. Afternoon speeches: Orell (part 2), Godfrey (part 1)
      Part 17: May 20. Afternoon speeches: Godfrey (part 2), Aspinall: Summary
    - "Learning, Leisure, Luxury: Romans and Villa on the Bay of Naples,", 1974 November 06 (Box 109)
      Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012012
    - "Probing the Egyptian Pyramids with Cosmic Rays,", circa 1970-1979 (Box 109)
      Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012007
    - 1975 Institute tapes, 1975 June 16 - July 3
      - Barnett and Pfaff lectures, 1975 July 2 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012237
        Part 1: Barnett; Part 2: Pfaff
      - Bertram Wolfe lecture, 1975 June 16 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012129
      - Edward Rozek lecture, 1975 July 3 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012108
      - Frank Shakespeare lecture, 1975 June 20 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012062
      - Judd and Jones lectures, 1975 June 18 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012053
        Part 1: Walter H. Judd; Part 2: Jones
      - Judd and Lloyd-Jones lectures, 1975 June 23 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012069
        Part 1: Walter H. Judd; Part 2: Lloyd-Jones
      - Judd and Thompson lectures, 1975 June 16 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012052
        Part 1: Walter H. Judd; Part 2: Robert Thompson
      - Judd and Thompson lectures, 1975 June 17 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012136
        Part 1: Walter H. Judd; Part 2: Sir Robert Thompson
      - Judd and Thompson lectures, 1975 June 18 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012142
      - Lloyd-Jones and Judd lectures, 1975 June 19 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012059
        Part 1: Lloyd-Jones; Part 2: Judd
      - Lloyd-Jones and Judd lectures, 1975 June 24 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012076
      - Lloyd-Jones and Judd lectures, 1975 July 3 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012238
      - Pap and Lloyd-Jones lectures, 1975 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012077
        Part 1: Michael Pap, 27 June 1975; Part 2: Dr. Lloyd-Jones, 3 July 1975
      - Robert Thompson lectures, 1975 June 16-17 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012130
        Part 1: 16 June 1975; Part 2: 17 June 1975
      - Rozek and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 30 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012212
        Part 1: Rozek; Part 2: Wolfe
      - Rozek and Wolfe lectures, 1975 July 2 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012217
      - Sir Robert Thompson lectures, 1975 June 18-19 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012143
        Part 1: Sir Robert Thompson, 18 June 1975; Part 2: Sir Robert Thompson, 19 June 1975
      - Sir Robert Thompson lectures, 1975 June 20-23 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012063
        Part 1: 20 June 1975. This talk ends suddenly (prematurely?) about thirty-five minutes on the accessioned cassette.
        Part 2: 23 June 1975
      - Sir Robert Thompson lectures, 1975 June 24-25 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012148, 2014c58_a_0012154
        Part 1: 24 June 1975; Part 2: 25 June 1975
      - Sir Robert Thompson lectures, 1975 June 26-27 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012159
        Part 1: 26 June 1975; Part 2: 27 June 1975, morning session
      - Sir Robert Thompson lecture, afternoon session, 1975 June 27 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012196
      - Taylor and Safran lectures, 1975 June 30 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012213
        Part 1: Ian Taylor; Part 2: William Safran
      - Thompson and Pap lectures, 1975 June 27 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012204
        Part 1: Sir Robert Thompson, afternoon; Part 2: Pap
      - Thompson and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 19 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012147
        Part 1: Robert Thompson; Part 2: Bertram Wolfe
      - Thompson and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 26 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012195
        Part 1: Sir Robert Thompson; Part 2: Bertram Wolfe
      - Thompson and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 27 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012203
      - Walter Judd P.M. lecture, 1975 July 1 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012216
      - Wolfe and Judd lectures, 1975 June 18 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012058
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe on the ambiguity of revolution. He speaks about the actual results of revolutions in contrast to the public aspirations of the revolutionaries. He focuses on the Soviet revolution, Lenin, and Stalin.
        Part 2: Walter Judd
      - Wolfe and Lloyd-Jones lectures, 1975 June 17-18 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012137
        Part 1: Wolfe, 17 June 1975; Part 2: Lloyd-Jones, 18 June 1975
      - Wolfe and Thompson lectures, 1975 June 23 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012068
        Part 1: Bertram Wolfe; Part 2: Robert Thompson
      - Wolfe, Faruk, and Jones lectures, 1975 June 23-24 (Box 110)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012158
        Part 1: Wolfe and Faruk (part 1), both from 23 June 1975; Part 2: Faruk (continued), 23 June 1975, and Jones, 24 June 1975
      - Edward Rozek lecture, 1975 July 3 (Box 111)
      - Greenberg lecture, 1975 June 25 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012106
      - Mott and Wolfe lectures, 1975 July 1 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012107
        Part 1: Mott; Part 2: Wolfe
      - Ostheimer lecture, 1975 June 26 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012105
      - Thompson and Nichols lectures, 1975 June 20 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012086
        Part 1: Sir Robert Thompson; Part 2: Dr. Tom Nichols
      - Thompson and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 24 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012087
        Part of Wolfe's lecture includes some stories of his time with Diego Rivera.
      - Thompson and Wolfe lectures, 1975 June 25 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012099
    - Conference on Détente, 1976
      - A lecture on communism in China, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013260
        Lord Lindsay examines communism in China, the philosophy of Mao Zedong, and how they apply to the rest of the world, especially the Soviet Union and the United States.
      - Communist strategy in Africa and the Indian Ocean, 1976 June 23 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013222
      - Conference on Détente discussions, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013250
      - Evening session, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013243
      - Historical Revisionism, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013223
        Intro - Shakespeare
      - Lecture on regional issues in the Middle East, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013249
      - Origins of Détente, 1976 June (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012804
      - The Origin of Cold War, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013259
      - Unidentified panel session, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013231
        This panel session occurred just before lunch.
      - Vanden Hecvel lecture, 1976 June (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012806
      - Willetts lecture, 1976 June 23 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012805
      - Willetts lecture, 1976 June (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0012807
      - World War III, 1976 (Box 111)
        Use copy reference number: 2014c58_a_0013237
    - Remainder of the sound cassettes are undescribed at this time
  - 36 sound microcassettes (Box 150)
- Videorecordings (Boxes 130, 151)
  Nine VHS videotapes, one U-matic videotape, and twelve open reel video tapes.
- Motion Picture Films (Film shelf)
  Comprised of three 16mm motion picture films.
  - "The Price of Peace and Freedom"
  - "Solzhenitsyn: Voice of Freedom"
  - "…Only the Strong…"
- Floppy Disks (Box 130)
  29 3 1/2 inch floppy disks.
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1939-2004 (Boxes 131-148)
  - Institute on Democracy and Communism materials, 1966-1982 (Box 131)
    Materials from the Institute on Democracy and Communism and the Institute for Comparative Study of Democracy and Communism.
    - "Academic Freedom and Academic Anarchy" by Sidney Hook, 1968 (Box-folder 131: 1)
    - Institute for the Study of Comparative Politics and Ideologies annual conference materials, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 131: 2-3)
      Also known as the Institute on Democracy and Communism and the Institute for Comparative Study of Democracy and Communism.
  - Solzhenitsyn Society for Freedom and Justice pamphlets, 1975 (Box-folder 131: 4)
  - Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought Materials, 1972-1985 (Box 131)
    - Publications from the Edward Teller Center for the Study of Democracy and Communism, 1972-1985 (Box-folder 131: 5)
      Later called the Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought.
    - Edward Teller Center financial report, undated (Box-folder 131: 6)
    - Memoranda and meeting minutes, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 131: 7)
    - Financial and budgeting materials, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 131: 8)
  - Biographical materials, 1957-1988 (Boxes 131-140)
    - "Profile in Academic Courage: Edward J. Rozek of the University of Colorado" by Ann Donnelly, 1988 (Box-folder 131: 9)
    - "Board of Regents Recommendations in the Matter of the Complaint of Edward J. Rozek against the Administrations of The University of Colorado,", undated (Box-folder 131: 10)
    - Scholarly articles, correspondence, various handwritten notes, and clippings, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 132: 1-4)
  - Teaching materials, 1940-2004
    Notes, articles, and printed matter regarding various topics, arranged alphabetically.
    - Biographies of notable historical figures, undated (Box-folder 132: 5-6)
    - Book summaries, undated (Box-folder 133: 1-3)
    - Bradley, Leo, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 133: 4)
    - Bulgaria, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 133: 5)
    - Chiang Kai-Shek, undated (Box-folder 133: 6)
    - China, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 133: 7-8)
    - China, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 134: 1-2)
    - Communism, 1956-1981 (Box-folder 134: 3)
    - Cuba, "Guerrilla Warfare: A Method" by Ernesto Che Guevara, 1964 (Box-folder 134: 4)
    - Czech Republic, 1968-1996 (Box-folder 134: 5)
    - Democracy, undated (Box-folder 134: 6)
    - Disarmament, 2002 (Box-folder 134: 7)
    - Eastern Europe, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 134: 8-10)
    - Education, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 134: 11)
    - England, 1993 (Box-folder 134: 12)
    - European Union, 1990 (Box-folder 135: 1)
    - France, 2003 (Box-folder 135: 2)
    - Germany, 1999 (Box-folder 135: 3)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 135: 4)
    - Greece, undated (Box-folder 135: 5)
    - Handouts, undated (Box-folder 135: 6)
    - Hilter, Adolf, undated (Box-folder 135: 7)
    - Hungary, 1958-1996 (Box-folder 135: 8)
    - Islam, 2001 (Box-folder 135: 9)
    - Japan, undated (Box-folder 135: 10)